[музыка]
Hello and Welcome to What's New in the
Project Management Project Management or
Project accounting is a very popular Mod
of Business Central andir because
contrib
economy As Services Professional
Services also in manufacturing we will
talk about it later My name is Andre and
I will be doing Demo For You demos of
New improvements in the current Release
which You will see in the very very
Short Time already seeing And It's a
continuation of effort which we started
like Long Time AG We Add valable
improvements to J Area in the warehouse
handling Now It's Time to do even More
so First of All we are
changing name From Jobs to Projects and
for some localizations It's a noticeable
change others
Will not notice it Because It's already
translated As A Project for Example in
Germany multiple UX improvements But
also couple of very High highly popular
product suggestion suggestions
registered on the ideas website Let's go
directly to the demos This is Project
Manager rolet Center and What you can
see you can see The Word Project All
Over The Place We you know that We
already use term Project In The Name Of
The rollet Center But also very often in
the documentation time to align so Now
We Can see Projects We Can see Project
registers journals Task etc But What if
you get used to the Word Job now you
Need to Type The Full name and It's
Might Be a Little Bit disruptive for
People Who is using this product For a
Long Time already so That's Why We
decided to Keep some backward
capabilities at least in the Search
terms Let's Go Here and search for Job
setup it Works Job
Journal it Works either that's a good
news So You can continue to
search terminology and it Will redirect
you to the places Where You
Right Let's open the Project list and
Minor improvements Here and there so we
have a Project details BX visible by
default But also you can Add via
personalization
What Power Bi BX So if you have a Power
Bi reports available you can Display
them Right Here Right Now also can can
Add Few
Fields ext
Back Back to the demonstration Let Open
The First Project which We see Here and
it has a lot of Lines I will Just
Go Del All of
them and can Location
Loc Case As Might useful scenar
involving warehouse handling and Now If
I will Create
New Project Task and Open
It Now in the Lines which I will be
adding the Location Code Will Be
initialized
Automatic do it One by can use New Fun
Select Items
sal and Area
As multiple cck and multiple L inserted
immediately so The Budget document
number and posting dates Will Be copied
From the previous line If
I in Advance OK What do we do Next We
proba Need to
initialize
caned
explode Bomb so The Same What we have in
sales Area But also recently added to
Transfer orders As well so We replaced
The assembly item with Its components
and the quantity is calculated correctly
based on quantity specified in the
Original item in the very
beginning
What do Next
also Project Takes Long time you Might
want to actually take
AE Take
snapshots How it evolves during during
the time you can do it automatically or
Man we have a new function Archive
Projects which can Create Archive
version
for I will cck and Here can number
have archived versions Because archived
document before I wasting As well So You
can see This is Original version with
All Lines and No Location and Here I
have a Restore Button which allows Me To
Go Back in Time
And Restore
Project Right Let's Go Back and find our
Project and see How it looks like it
looks absolutely Same
limitations of What We Can and cannot
Restore in the documentation and the
Release Notes Release Notes is usually
very good Source which describes What is
added in the recent rele with All
nuances allr Let's Go and Explore More
assembly
Pro
of used in the engineer to Order scenar
When You Need to Build huge and is like
Very Very Custom so sem repeatable so in
This Case Sub components can be
delivered As assemblies allr I have a
Project created in Advance and Here I
Can navig My Pro list of Project And I
have already four Lines demonstrating
different flavors of assembly to Order
functionality you can already notice
that there is quantity to assemble Field
which is Works in very similar Way What
you know From sales document sales
orders let me go Here and initialize the
quantity Let's use Six F is not enough
and Because This
specific item is configured to use
assembly policy AS assemble to
Order quantity to assemble gets
populated immediately let me Scroll Down
in the item Card and Show You The
assembly policy assembly to Order OK so
System respects This setting And then
you can navigate to assemble Order and
see what what
Here And you can navigate backwards As
well to Project Lines From B so both
directions all right Let's Close This
One
Let's Take A Look at couple of other
examples What If assembly policy is
assembly to Stock again similar to What
we have in the sales Area you can Just
Enter quantity Here
and And you can get Lines created or
assembly Order created automatically All
Right You can see that I'm using
different locations Because I Wanted to
demonstrate How it Works for different
W settings in the Main Location I have
actually any fyh Processing Let Just cck
Home Create
Journal Open
journ
mple transactions created Let's Explore
item Ledger entry What do we see
assembly consumption Two components Get
consumed minus minus minus And you
notice The quantity IS F Because We
actually assembling F Out Of Five But We
Wanted to use All five probably One was
built ear and was available on the Stock
so The
Will
qu qu From for
Example SY beh in This
Case behaves properly it
produces
SY need
need consume First Al that was Basic
scenar
with Simple handing Let's Go and Explore
A Little Bit More Advanced cases for
Example Let's initial quantity for
Yellow Location which in This scenario I
configure to use
inventory not a usual configuration Why
highlighting it and for inventory I can
also do different quantity and quantity
to assemble But not forare PE for peak I
configured Location to use Peaks in this
scenar This One is More demanding so it
has Only Two options like Zero Original
quantity so I can Here beware limitation
If can always
spit
that difficult mitigate This limitation
If You Need to separate approaches alr
Let's Create warehouse Documents Let
Start with
inventory Need to Put Activate Create
inventory tole and cck
OK created navigate to
Lines alr I have My inventory for Yellow
document Points to Job usage and it
shows The item which I need To assemble
and use and Let's Put quantity Let's
quantity 3 preview
posting As expected for transactions
consumption consumption output and then
adjustment If necessary And of course it
Works If I will use for Example lower
quantity like to Post preview
posting Let's go to item Ledger entries
From our find entries Button and see OK
components consumed something is
produced and
immediately used for for For The Job
allr Let's go to warehouse scenario
Let's Close This ones and We Are Back in
the Project Card Where I can Create
warehouse peak
Create for Case for Silver Location
Let's Go
related
PS and We Can
Lines Because in This Case for House We
Need to Pick components so Taking
components Take Place Take
Place differentes ming assem Area and
register can can
po Once
registered We Can navigate to Project
planning
cines Create
line in the
Journal I will Remove This line Because
it's not needed for our
can for Silver Location Let's Now Try To
posting
preview and You can see that System
consumed components produced The item
and also used It For for
Jobs that is about assembly to Order
scenario Now As I mentioned Projects can
be like big and Long and they also can
involve multiple
parties and We Need to invoice This
Project sometimes partially to different
participants Let's Take A Look What we
can do in the current version I have Two
Projects which are Very Very
identical For The reason and Here you
can see I have three Lines three Lines
and Maybe it's not Always Enough to
use One Cell To and One Build to
customer default customer you Might want
actually to do it More granular so for
Example we want to do it per per Task
and in This Case we have a new
setting multiple
customer which you can also default in
the Project setup let me go quickly to
the Project
setup
and Show You All New settings we have
Here So You can see that billing is
configured in the General section And
behaves absolutely The Same Way like As
other default values So You can
initialize New Project Create with
following values But then you can change
them manually like apply usage Link or
different posting Group
anding Method also that we have
archiving
I activated My tasking to multiple
Because I already have
Lines then customer and Build to
customer you can see The New Fields
which are Now visible they were
initialized based On values in the
document itself I can change them Here
later noce that I cannot Switch back for
multiple to one customer and there is
also no synchronization From the header
to Lines So if I will decide to CH My M
customer it Will propagate Data to the
Job Task Now they are on the own It's
users Task to Keep them current and
updated allr Let's experiment Let's
change The different Bill to customer
Right and What
happened We see that prices Get updated
so Now Price is actually 222 Because Now
we have a different billing customer
can
Backs And you can SY Asking If I want to
update prices or not Yes I would like to
update prices in This Case and Drill
Down Here Now The Price
is made it Simple so We Can see The
difference between different Building
customers All Let's Go modif other other
Lines we have a different bu Here Yes We
update related Lines We Can also change
The sell to customer
OK We agree with the update of Build To
customer and also recalculation of
prices All Good probably you know that
it's not enough to Deal with Only
Numbers so sometimes you want to change
different settings As well Let's go to
the New Card which is Now attached to
the each Pro TAS can butt View and
edil cck and it op The Project Task Card
which looks like As A Small Project Card
so it has sell to customer you can
define also External document Number Let
do External 30 you can define The
reference
can
The Line editing Here and we have Select
Lines assembly to Order actions
reservation actions Let's also Scroll
Down and We Can see different methods
you can overwrite Location Code for
Project Task As well and bin Code And
you can decide which Build to customer
to use and and other other other
parameters like payment terms payment
Method and currency
Let
currency Point I currency of course it
Will change prices Here Because We
prices defined in the Project currency
Def per Project But Once We Will Be
doing invoicing currency is considered
and Let's do invoicing Let's Go Here and
search for Project
invoices Pro
have
Remember 202 Plus
currency
sales
and 100000 in the buil to customer
different buil to customer and the last
One is
20,000 you can also see The External
document Number received From the Job
Task
line OK Let's open the document Take A
Look A Little Bit More What else We see
Here We see The reference We see The
External
document We see All Lines The currency
and
recn Price looks it converted into curr
invoicing currency specified payment
terms payment
methods All Good What else I Wanted to
show you
Here Because Project Business
is difficult We would like to give you
an Extra
flexibility dealing with invoicing
instead of crees
Jobs Let's Go
Here Lines functions Get Project
planning
Lines and can see that there is Another
Project from a different Project
Remember I had
Two
This
currency Now I have Two Lines From Two
different
Projects
simil If I will go to a different
invoice let me
Open The First One which is very Simple
One Because
popust
Open
Scroll
Down line functions Get Project planning
Lines As I mention This combination to
bu To and empty currency is More popular
and used in More Demo Projects we have
so That's Why you can see The More Lines
and We Can
also Select All and Add All
of Projects Into The Single invoice so
it Works very similar to attach line
scenario which
from a different Window But you can do
it in buk From from a different
Perspective So You can do it From
invoice Let's Take A Look at What We
Learn or so in This Demo so We know that
Projects Now Jobs are Now called
Projects you know that you can use other
functionality familiar by sales Area
such As Select Items explode Bomb
archiving orders Works very similar Way
assemble To Projects also Works very
similar Way And gives you a good
flexibility also It is much easier and
More Flexible to
dealing When You Need to Build multiple
customers or When you Build multiple
Projects All At
Once Thank you Thank you for watching
and thank you for other things thank you
for submitting ideas thank you for
contributing in
discussion engage and thank you for
participating in preview testing and
Sharing your early Feedback As well you
Might also want to see other sessions in
This in This Event Because We also did
improvements Into The service Area we
also have a Field Service integration
Now available As well and again Group of
improvements related To timesheet and
Data
entry useful
resources Thank
you
L